https://www.ionos.co.uk/terms-gtc/terms-privacy/

Tax Strategy
Below you can see our new GDPR compliant privacy policy. You can find further information and a checklist for IONOS customers in our Help Center.
Privacy policy 1&1 IONOS Ltd.
For 1&1 IONOS Ltd. (" IONOS"), protecting your personal data is a priority. We comply with all relevant data protection legislation and the following privacy notice is intended to provide transparency about how we handle your personal data.
Personal data and the provision of services
When you order one of our products, we only ask for information that is essential to deliver our products and services to you or for invoicing reasons. In most cases this is limited to name, address, contact data and bank details.
Contract and invoicing data
Prior to sign up On the IONOS web pages we offer prospective and actual customers practical tools and services, for example, to check how easy it is to locate your website or company on the Internet. The tool needs only some basic address data. For the best results and continuous improvement of our services, your entries are recorded anonymously.Sign up Upon ordering our products, we ask for data we need to provision the services. Your data is stored securely on our systems and you are able to access and change your data in our control panel. Information on how you access the control panel will usually be sent by email or alternatively by post.Billing In order to provide you with transparent billing, it is necessary to temporarily store certain usage data. Examples include your configurations of our Cloud-Server or performance of our Webhosting products, if those are the basis for billing. Whether your product usage data is recorded, will be in the respective product chapter in this privacy notice.
Usage and content data
Usage data We aim to provide quality and reliability but on occasion, issues may arise. In order to react quickly, it may be necessary to temporarily record usage and traffic data to provide to our Support staff. We do this to ensure we fulfil our obligations to you and to design products and services aligned to your needsContent data We offer certain products, for example, online storage or email accounts, where personal files may be stored. These files are automatically encrypted and may only be viewed by individuals with access rights. In order to protect your data and for maintenance purposes, we create and file encrypted backups. The file contents of these backups cannot be decrypted or viewed by us.
Usage of your data
The usage of your personal data Some of your personal data we need for processing your order and for providing customer focused services.Data processing upon receiving your order Our commitment to you is to provide value for money top products and services to our customers. In order to ensure smooth and trouble-free order processes, your order is thoroughly vetted and invest in fraud prevention before confirming your contract.Contract and customer information You will receive the order confirmation and information by email. We use the email address you have provided to order the product. You will also receive your invoices and helpful information in the same manner.Product information In order to fully capture the benefits of our products, we send you tips, tricks and useful complementing product solutions by email and control panel. We may also inform you about interesting new products via telephone, provided that you have consented to receive such information. . If you wish to stop receiving information of this kind, you can always revoke your consent in the control panel.Usage data as part of our services and products Certain data is recorded during the use of our products and services to enable us to identify issues with our products and to continuously improve our products and services. We implement a range of technological and organizational measures to protect your privacy and ensure the safety of your personal data.Personal data managed by you Our customers use our services to host, transmit or process data on our hosting platforms, which may include personal data of their own customers. In this scenario, it is our customers who stipulate the process for collecting their customer’s data. Most importantly, we do not have knowledge of or view, share or collect this specific customer data. In accordance with our Privacy Notice, it is our customers who are responsible for managing the security of their customers’ data which they upload onto our platforms. Customers are responsible for encrypting data that is uploaded to our network and ensuring access to our platforms are secure. Our relationship is with our customers directly and there is no agreement in place between us and our customers’ customers. Additionally: We merely process such data on your behalf, subject to our Terms and Conditions and you are responsible for any applicable legal requirements in respect of your content. Therefore, any video, image, or other content posted, uploaded or otherwise made available by you onto your website, whether published content or not, is not subject to our Privacy Notice.Opinion polls In order to offer you the best possible products and services, we do need your support. Therefore, we send out surveys to our customers from time to time via email or provide them on our websites. Participation in these surveys is optional and you may revoke your consent to receiving opinion polls from us after the first email.Improving our products and services We have a legitimate interest to analyze the data we collect to improve our products and services. We use a variety of methods and tools to do this. As described in this policy, we collect data that relates to you; your usage of our products and services; and your interactions with us, for example when we send you correspondence, you contact our Customer Care department, or complete a survey. We also collect public data and data from third-parties to better understand our customers‘ needs. We protect your privacy through a range of technical and organizational measures tailored to each situation and respect your choices about how we use your data.
Transferring data to third parties
1&1 IONOS Ltd. is a group company of United Internet AG We, and other subsidiaries and affiliates, are part of United Internet AG. In order to avoid duplicate copies of address data and adhere to negative data, as for example email black lists, it is sometimes necessary to transfer customer data to United Internet AG and its affiliates.External partner companies As we work with selected partners to offer you a wide range of products and sometimes act as an intermediary for our partners, it is necessary to transfer certain personal data to third parties, for example, registering domain names or issuing SSL certificates.Law enforcement Occasionally, we are obliged to disclose personal data to prosecution authorities and courts for law enforcement purposes. We always ask for the correct paperwork before disclosing any information.Reporting of faulty products and fraud In case of faulty products or disagreements and we are committed to seek amicable solutions. Is this not possible, we evaluate the situation carefully, when and to whom we report faulty products or fraudulent usage.
Cookies
For more information on the cookies we use, please click here.
Service specific data protection information
Website Live-chatPurpose of processing Quality AssuranceCategories of personal data Content data, usage data, traffic dataLegal basis Legitimate Interests, Art 6(1) lit. f GDPRRetention period Up to 90 daysSubprocessors optimise-it GmbH, Hamburg, GermanyDomain CheckPurpose of processing Domain name requests are stored and processed to improve the domain name suggestion and products. This requests will never be used by IONOS to register domains on own behalf.Categories of personal data Processed domain name data are not linked to any customer or contract.
Product specific data protection information
List of our current subprocessors With some of our products we rely on the expertise of specialised partner companies to ensure that we provide the best possible products and services experience. In the event you cease to use our products and services, we will delete your personal data within a given timeframe.
Address Book
Purpose of processing Provide central contact management functionality for creating, managing, and synchronizing contact informationCategories of personal data Contact data, content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit b GDPRRetention period 30 days after termination of contract
Webhosting
Content Delivery Network CDNPurpose of processing Distribute website assets through multiple data centres to increase website performance.Categories of personal data Content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Cloudflare, San Francisco, USAhttps://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/SiteLockPurpose of processing Protect and clean your website from malware.Categories of personal data Content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRRetention period SiteLock stores the webspace of customer for 30 days (the grace period). Deletion of personal data is within 90 days after cleanup.Subprocessors SiteLock, Scottsdale, USA
MyWebsite
Current product generation MyWebsite NowPurpose of processing The processing and publication of the website, and hosting of the website.Categories of personal data Content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Equinex Datacenter, Frankfurt, Germany MyWebsite Creator, eCommerce, EssentialWebsite EditorPurpose of processing Editing and publishing of websiteCategories of personal data Content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Duda Inc., Tel Aviv, Israel Amazon Web Services, Inc., Seattle WA, USAWebspacePurpose of processing Hosting of websiteCategories of personal data Content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors AWS - Amazon Web Services, Datacentre Frankfurt, Germany Amazon Web Services, Inc., Seattle WA, United StatesContent Delivery Network (CDN)Purpose of processing Hosting of website; distribute website assets through multiple data centres to maximize website performance.Categories of personal data Content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors AWS - Amazon Web Services ‘Cloud Front’, Datacentre Frankfurt, Germany Amazon Web Services, Inc., Seattle WA, United StatesOnline Business CardPurpose of processing Fast publishing of an online business card. You have the choice of which information will be displayed on this business card. User data will be sent to Google and Facebook in order to display publicly available information.Categories of personal data Contact data, content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Google LLC, Mountain View CA, USA Facebook, Menlo Park CA, USAShopPurpose of processing Seamless integration of an online shop in the Website-Editor.Categories of personal data Contact data, content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Ecwid, Encinitas CA, USARoute descriptionPurpose of processing MyWebsite uses address data to show the location of a company on a map. In order to do so the product transfers this data to Mapbox. This happens when you set up the first project.Categories of personal data Address data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Mapbox, Washington D.C., USAWebsite TranslatorPurpose of processing If you set up multilanguage texts: MyWebsite sends the text content of the website to Google Translate in order to translate the content to one or several other languages.Categories of personal data Content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Google LLC, Mountain View CA, USAWebfontsPurpose of processing Load google webfonts to accelerate loading the website and to enable consistent presentation of the website on various platforms and applications.Categories of personal data Usage data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Google LLC, Mountain View CA, USAMulti LocationPurpose of processing MyWebsite uses address data to mark one or several locations of a company on a map. Data is sent to the map company Mapbox. This takes place automatically when adding this widget and with additional locations.Categories of personal data Address data, content dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Mapbox, Washington D.C., USA Interactive product tourPurpose of processing Guided interactive product tour to help customers set up and use the website editor.Categories of personal data Subscriber data, usage data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRRetention period 180 daysSubprocessors Userlane GmbH, Munich, Germany Consent ManagementPurpose of processing Provision and operation of a consent management function for the website. Website visitors can give their consent for processing and setting cookies and receive information about the functions applied and how data are used.Categories of personal data Subscriber data, usage data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Usercentrics GmbH, Munich, Germany
MyWebsite (Vers. 8)
Google MapsPurpose of processing MyWebsite 8 transfers address data of the customer to Google in order to prefill address data in the Google maps module or if selected sends another stored address to Google.Categories of personal data Address data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Google LLC, Mountain View, USAMy DataPurpose of processing On the publishing of the MyWebsite homepage customer and other user defined data will be added to the website in schema.org format, in order to support search engines and improve SEO results.Categories of personal data Contact data, content dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPRMyShopPurpose of processing Editing, maintenance and operation of online shops.Categories of personal data Contact data, content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period Shop data will be deleted 31 days after end of contract lifetime.Subprocessors ePages, Hamburg, Germany
Domain & SSL Certificate
DomainPurpose of processing Registering, transfer, configuration, maintenance and deletion of the domain nameCategories of personal data Subscriber dataLegal basis Performance of a contract or at your request prior to entering into a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period Differs for the various top level domains (TLDs) depending on the Registrar Accreditation Agreement (RAA) of the registry.Subprocessors A dedicated overview for regitries and escrow provider is available here.SSL certificatePurpose of processing Registering, transfer, configuration, maintenance and deletion of SSL certificates. Automatic processing in MyWebsite products when connecting the domain with the website project.Categories of personal data Subscriber dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors DigiCert, Lehi UT, USANote In the process of acquisition and maintenance of SSL certificates, IONOS is only an intermediary between the customer and the respective issuer of the SSL certificate. IONOS has no influence on the issuance of certificates and does not accept any liability that the certificate is assigned to the customer and that it will permanently exist.
IONOS Shop, E-Mail & Office & and more
IONOS Shop (current Version)Please refer to the 'MyWebsite Creator, eCommerce, Essential' Section for more information. IONOS Shop (previous Version)Purpose of processing Editing, maintenance and operation of online shops.Categories of personal data Contact data, content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period Shop data will be deleted 31 days after end of contract lifetime.Subprocessors ePages, Hamburg, GermanyIONOS MailPurpose of processing Provision of email services, including setting up, configuring and deleting email addressesCategories of personal data Subscriber data, content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period 7 days after deletion of content, all data will be purged 7 days past end of contract lifetimeSubprocessors Open-Xchange, Cologne, Germany Email archivingPurpose of processing Archiving of e-mailsCategories of personal data Subscriber data, content data, usage data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period 60 days after end of contractSubprocessors Strato AG, Berlin, GermanyHosted ExchangePurpose of processing Provision of email services, including setting up, configuring and deleting email addressesCategories of personal data Subscriber data, content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period End of contract lifetimeSubprocessors Fasthosts Internet Limited, Gloucester, United KingdomMicrosoft Office 365Purpose of processing Usage of Microsoft Office 365, including setting up, configuring and deletion of accounts and usersCategories of personal data Subscriber data, content data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period User data will be stored up to one year after termination of the license.Subprocessors Microsoft, Redmond WA, USA T-Systems International, Frankfurt am Main, GermanyOX App SuitePurpose of processing Usage of OX App Suite, including setting up, configuring and deletion of accounts and usersCategories of personal data Subscriber data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period User data will be stored up to one year after termination of the last license.Subprocessors Open-Xchange, Cologne, Germany G SuitePurpose of processing Usage of Google G Suite, including set up, configuration, deletion and customer service.Categories of personal data Subscriber data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Google LLC, Mountain View CA, USAhttps://gsuite.google.com/intl/en/terms/subprocessors.htmlhttps://policies.google.com/privacyHiDrive Cloud StoragePurpose of processing Providing cloud storage for you and your users for worldwide access from any device at any time.Categories of personal data Subscriber data, content data, usage data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period Up to 4 month past end of contract lifetimeSubprocessors Strato AG, Berlin, Germany  MyBackupPurpose of processing Provisioning and the use of the backup. Customer service and operation of the platform.Categories of personal data Subscriber data, content data, usage dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period Time that the data was stored according to the settings you assigned. Latest by the end of the contract lifetime.Subprocessors STRATO AG, Berlin, GermanyList LocalPurpose of processing Publishing and synchronisation of company data in online listings to improve rankings in search enginesCategories of personal data Contact data, content dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period 30 days past end of contract lifetimeSubprocessors uberall, Berlin, GermanyrankingCoachPurpose of processing Optimisation of search rankings of your websites in Google search engine. With the Pro version you can additionally set up Google Ads campaigns.Categories of personal data Subscriber data, Contact data, usage dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors rankingCoach, Cologne, GermanyGoogle Ads Management Service (Search Engine Marketing)Purpose of processing Setting up and managing Google Ads campaigns for your website.Categories of personal data Subscriber data, content data, usage dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period 30 daysSubprocessors Jellyfish, Warrington, UKEmail MarketingPurpose of processing Creation, sending and monitoring of newsletter campaigns.Categories of personal data Contact data, content data, usage data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period User data will be stored up to one year past end of the contract lifetime.Subprocessors Mailjet, Paris, FranceIONOS Online Accounting (Shutdown September 2019)Purpose of processing Online accounting and billingCategories of personal data Subscriber data, content dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period End of contract lifetimeSubprocessors SEVENIT, Offenburg, GermanyHosting Mobile AppPurpose of processing Mobile access to the IONOS Control-Centre.Categories of personal data Subscriber data, usage dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR, Legitimate interest Art. 6, para. 1, lit. of the GDPRRetention period Subscriber data is stored until the app is uninstalled. 12 months for usage dataTracking Statistical evaluation of the app's usage are only used internally. Your IP address will be anonymised and not merged with other data. The data collected in this way does not reveal any details about your identity.Subprocessors Adobe Analytics, San José CA, USA Google LLC, Mountain View CA, USA Video ChatPurpose of processing Provision and operation of an online video conference with invitation function for participants.Categories of personal data Content data, contact data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period Traffic data is deleted after 2 days, content data and contact data are not stored.Subprocessors Starface GmbH, Karlsruhe, GermanyIONOS WebAnalyticsPurpose of processing Statistical analysis and technical optimization of your website.Categories of personal data Anonymized usage and traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRServer The following information applies to Managed Cloud, Virtual Private Servers (VPS), Cloud Servers, Dedicated Servers, Dynamic Cloud Servers and Virtual Server products: With the listed products, you as our custonmer solely control which personal data is beeing processed in which way.Categories of personal data In your sole discretionRetention period In your sole discretionLegal basis In your sole discretionSubprocessors In your sole discretion Additionally, the following instructions apply to the use of certain (partial) functions for these products:Virtual Private Servers (VPS), Cloud Servers, Dedicated Servers, Dynamic Cloud Servers, Virtual Server and Cloud Backup. Cloud BackupPurpose of processing Provisioning and the use of Cloud Backup. Customer service and operation of the platform.Categories of personal data Subscriber data, content data, usage dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period Time that the data was stored according to the settings you assigned. Latest by the end of the contract lifetime.Subprocessors STRATO AG, Berlin, Germany Availability check customer serverPurpose of processing Monitoring Service to check the server availability of the customer during relocations or support requests.Categories of personal data Subscriber dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRSubprocessors Monitis US LLC, Florida, USA PLESKPurpose of processing Provisioning and the use of the server administration software.Categories of personal data Subscriber dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period End of contract lifetimeSubprocessors Plesk International GmbH, Schaffhausen, CH Switzerland VirtuozzoPurpose of processing Provision and use of virtualization software for virtual servers, which were acquired before 07/2016.Categories of personal data Subscriber data, Content data, usage data, traffic dataLegal basis Performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPRRetention period End of contract lifetimeSubprocessors Virtuozzo International GmbH, Schaffhausen, CH Switzerland
Transparency is our aim
All data we receive from you during the lifetime of your contract is used primarily to provide the level of service you would expect. We carry out statistical analyses to improve products and services. These analyses are conducted in compliance with data protection legislation and our internal privacy policies and processes.Your rights In respect of Art. 15 GDPR you have the right to obtain information as to wether or not your personal data are beeing processed. You also have the right to have your personal data rectified if it is inaccurate in accordance with Art. 16 GDPR, a right to be forgotten (Art. 17 GDPR), a right to obtain restriction of processing under given cirumstances (Art. 18 GDPR) and the right to data portability stated in Art. 20 GDPR. You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, as to where the processing is based on Art. 6(1) lit f GDPR. If you wish to exercise one of these rights, please contact our data protection officer and we get this done for you.Please email:privacynotice@ionos.co.ukSupervisory authorities You have the right to file a complaint with any supervisory authority. Here you will find the contact information for the UK Information Commissioner's Office: Information Commissioner's Office Wycliffe House Water Lane Wilmslow Cheshire SK9 5AF Tel: 0303 123 1113 You can download or print this Version with the functions 'Print page' or 'Create PDF' at the end of this page. Last update: December 2020
Content
Privacy policy 1&1 IONOS Ltd.
MyWebsite (Vers. 8)
Domain & SSL Certificate
IONOS Shop, E-Mail & Office & and more
Transparency is our aim
To top
